welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we go here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
[Music]
all right can I get a thumbs up if
everyone can hear me and see my screen
right now okay great
so if you're here last week then you're
already familiar with the premise for
these weekly sessions here we are
prototyping digital gangs to help people
maintain their sovereignty and to
respond to the meta crisis for tonight
I'm gonna start by quickly reviewing
what we talked about last week for the
people who weren't here and then the
rest of the time I actually want to go
into breakout groups and actually have
more of an in-person interaction so
there will be less talking but to begin
again some housekeeping please turn on
your video if you can do that go for it
we're all new recording speaker view so
you can you can be a little bit more
vulnerable and don't have to worry about
anything personal being shared also a
reminder to use the chat feel free to
have a parallel conversation feel free
to ask and answer each other's questions
and also finally lean in to making
friends see if you can find people to
follow on Twitter or private message
somebody if they share something that
you like okay this is really the premise
like how can we use accountability to
maintain sovereignty and respond to the
medic crisis and I'm gonna try to sum up
everything we talked about last week in
this singular slide so this is where we
want to go right there's a crisis right
now and it's unclear what each
individual is supposed to do in response
to it
last week we talked about how the
quality of a response to this crisis is
going to be a product of our ability to
make good choices and our ability to
make sense of what's going on to know up
from down and all of that rests on
something called personal sovereignty
which I defined as your capacity to
respond to something as opposed to react
to it the opposite of personal
sovereignty would be when you get
emotionally activated by something
and from there it gets a lot less
abstract we talked about how personal
sovereignty is really the product of
managing your physiology and managing
your addictions in the camp of
physiology we talked about how sleep
nutrition exercise and meditation are
the fundamentals and to the extent that
we are practicing these things we are up
regulating our sovereignty and we talk
about managing our addictions and how we
live in an environment full of
supernormal stimuli all these dopamine
activating vehicles that continually
draw our attention away from what
matters most so some examples being
social media news pornography and video
games and so managing your addictions is
another fundamental step for personal
sovereignty and all of this is going to
be upregulated through accountability
and this is what I'm referring to as the
metagame mastermind or these digital
gangs in summary to manage your
physiology last week we talked about
life practices so maybe waking up early
is an example for managing your
addictions we talked about negation so
deleting your Netflix account would be a
negation and in the third category that
we started to get into but is admittedly
the most challenging of the three was
giving your best gifts for the current
moment and that all throw in the camp of
a response to the meta crisis so these
mastermind groups that were prototyping
this digital gang is going to be in
service of these three and tonight I
want to go specifically into this one
what does it mean to give your best gift
how can we take a first pass at
discovering what that is and this first
pass idea I am framing it as a
provisional purpose what's basically
something provisional something for a
period of time that you can perhaps
commit to with a group of people that
you can think of as a shitty first draft
of your best gifts for the current
moment last week I got some really
interesting feedback about how when you
say best gift it's kind of daunting it
makes you think of something that might
take you years to discover and so
tonight we're going to compress that as
much as possible and see if we can get a
clue as to what that gift might be here
are some clues about gifts so I took
this from this really great article
which I'll share at the end
Danish Mountain burger on how to inquire
into what your purpose could be and he
broke it down into these three
categories your capacities values and
propensity capacities refer to what is
possible in your life right now
values have to do with what you think is
right and propensity is there what are
you drawn to maybe your your talents are
also in this category so we're gonna get
into a breakout session but before I do
that I just want to share this quote
that I got from Richard Bartlett which I
think adds another layer of significance
to what what's emerging here so
everyone's been talking about the meta
crisis we're talking about how Kovach 19
is just the beginning of something
bigger and something much more
complicated and there have been many
different ways of framing what this
bigger more complicated thing is and I
found this recently I'm just gonna read
it to you I believe that the core of
this bio socio psycho-spiritual collapse
is a meta crisis of relationship it's
about how I relate to the different
parts of myself to other people and to
all of the creatures life spirit etc on
this planet if that's true then my
response must be relational first the
reason why I'm highlighting this is
because whatever we explore in the
remainder of our time tonight in these
breakout groups it gives us an
opportunity to actually respond to this
relational piece to the extent that you
are practicing right relation with the
person that you're talking to on zoom'
to the extent that you're being as
non-ego ik as possible or as present as
possible in the way that you relate to
them you are doing by this framing one
small part in responding to the medic
races and so I really want to prompt
myself first and foremost but everybody
else here to get out of the frame of you
know we're discussing something that
we're going to do later and actually
think we're doing the thing right now
and without further delay let's get into
this breakout activity so these are
going to be eight-minute sessions in a
minute I'm going to break everybody up
into groups of two and you're gonna have
four minutes for each person to ask a
question
to the other person and the questions
will all go into the chat and they will
have to do with your capacities your
values and your propensity and the goal
is to come up with a provisional purpose
a shitty first draft of your best gift
for the current moment so I'm going to
stop sharing my screen